# William Smale

London / United Kingdom | +44 75 4762 1774 | smale.will@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Personal Website

## **SUMMARY**

An outgoing, industrious individual, with demonstrated enthusiasm and competency in application and infrastructure security with 5+ years experience in IT security.

KEY SKILLS: Python, Terraform, GitLab, HashiCorp Vault, CI/CD, OWASP, Penetration Testing, Kubernetes, Docker, Bash, SQL, Solidity, Linux, Windows, MacOS, GitHub, Threat Modelling, Burp, Wiz, Cycode, AWS, Google Cloud, Azure, DAST, SAST, SCA

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**GFK** London, UK IT Security Analyst April 2023 - Present

• Owner of asset management; Developed and deployed a service that tracks and categorises domains across the company.

- Owner of bug bounty program; Triaged bug reports and assisted development teams in remediation.
- Vulnerability management reporting; Automation of the reporting process.
- Driving the shift left policy; Defining & implementing pipelines end to end.
- Performed educational workshops for development teams.
- Collaborating with a team across multiple time zones: USA, UK, Germany, India, and Malaysia.
- Worked through a merger and a divestment of the business.

Quantum Gate London, UK

DevSecOps Engineer

September 2022 – February 2023

- Led the design and deployment of CI/CD pipelines. Mentored development team in 'shifting left'.
- Deployed and managed Docker Swarm, implemented Graylog, elastic search and MariaDB for monitoring and logging.

Telic Consulting Johannesburg, RSA March 2018 – March 2022

Security Engineer

Successfully secured sensitive company and customer information. Deployed a centralised key management capability across MTN's footprint improving the organisation's security posture, bringing the company in line with GDPR.

#### MTN - Lead Architect

- Led the implementation, integration and training of the new key management capability across 13 countries.
- Designed and adapted the key management reference architecture in line with unique requirements and use cases highlighted by stakeholders within each country targeted for deployment.
- Drafted key management policy and standard documentation in line with stakeholder requirements and industry best practices (NIST, ISO).

#### MTN - Business Analyst

- Identified key platforms, to be secured, that processed or stored sensitive company/customer information.
- Gathered technical requirements from key stakeholders across the company for multiple RFPs.
- Provided support to multiple countries, analysed their environment, identified crown jewel systems, facilitated knowledge transfer between countries, tracked program progress, and addressed the implementation team's blockers.
- Conducted gap analyses of threat intelligence platforms to determine the necessity of RFP/RFI.
- Developed documentation in line with stakeholder requirements and industry best practices (NIST, ISO), including:
  - Key management and data encryption policies, standards and processes.
  - Drafting segmentation of duties(SoD) application standards, assisting in requirements gathering for SoD RFP.

#### Discovery Bank - Security Analyst

- Administered Splunk. Provisioned user access and built dashboards in line with stakeholder requirements.
- Conducted analysis of existing production architecture, to determine alignment with target reference architecture.
- Developed data analytics tools using Python/Pandas for vulnerability data processing and aggregated reporting.

# William Smale

London / United Kingdom | +44 75 4762 1774 | smale.will@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Personal Website

## LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

**GFK** London, UK

IT Security Analyst

April 2023 - Present

- Owner of asset management; Developed and deployed a service that tracks and categorises domains across the company.
- Owner of bug bounty program; Triaged bug reports and assisted development teams in remediation.
- Performed educational workshops for development teams.

Quantum Gate London, UK

DevSecOps Engineer

September 2022 – February 2023

• Led the design and deployment of CI/CD pipelines. Mentored development team in 'shifting left'.

**Telic Consulting** Security Engineer

Johannesburg, RSA

March 2018 - March 2022

- Led the implementation and integration process of the key management capability across ~13 target countries.
- Providing support to multiple countries in analysing their environments, identifying systems, prioritising systems, tracking program progress, facilitating knowledge transfer, and addressing the implementation team's blockers.

## **EDUCATION**

**Rhodes University** Grahamstown, RSA

BSc Honours in Computer Science

2017 2013 - 2016

BSc in Computer Science & Information Systems

Balgowan, RSA

Michaelhouse Matric

2008 - 2012

#### **CURRENT STUDIES**

Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP)

### **SKILLS**

## Programming Languages & Technologies:

Python, Bash, SQL, Solidity, C#, RegEx

## **Tools & Platforms:**

AWS, Google Cloud, Azure, Terraform, HashiCorp Vault, Kubernetes, Docker, Linux, Windows, MacOS, Burp, Synk, Cycode, Wiz, GitLab, GitHub

### **Processes & Frameworks:**

CI/CD, OWASP, Penetration Testing, Threat Modelling, DAST, SAST, SCA

#### **INTERESTS**

Information Security, Penetration Testing, Smart Contracts, Diving, Chess, Maui Thai, Gaming, Philosophy, Birding, Travel

## WILL PROVIDE REFERENCES ON REQUEST